Carroll L.V. Meeks Collection of Ephemera on Various Architects
Yale University Arts Library
Carroll L.V. Meeks Collection of Ephemera on Various Architects
1950-1960
VRC 320
Yale University Arts Library
3.11
9 boxes
Collection of ephemera, including articles, newspaper clippings, brochures, pamphlets, and photographs started by Yale Professor Carroll L.V. Meeks. Upon his death, the collection was given by his daughters to the Yale University Arts Library and maintained in the Visual Resources Collection where department staff added material on occasion.
Meeks, Carroll L. V. (Carroll Louis Vanderslice), 1907-1966
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
Collection of ephemera, including articles, newspaper clippings, brochures, pamphlets, and photographs started by Yale Professor Carroll L.V. Meeks. Upon his death, the collection was given by his daughters to the Yale University Arts Library and maintained in the Visual Resources Collection where department staff added material on occasion.
Arrangement
In folders, arranged alphabetically by name of architect or architectural firm.
Architects; Photographs; Reproductions
- Aalto, Alvar (Box 1)
- Adam Brothers (1728-1796) (Box 1)
- Alberti [Leon Battista, 1404-1472] (Box 1)
- Ando, Tadao (Box 1)
- Arquitectonica (Box 1)
- Austin, Henry [1804-1891], (3 folders and copy of inventory of Henry Austin papers in Manuscripts & Archives) (Box 1)
- Bacon, Henry (Box 1)
- Barber, Donn (Box 1)
- Barnes, Edward Larrabee (Box 1)
- Becket, Welton and Associates (Box 1)
- Beckford [William] (Box 1)
- Belluschi, Pietro (Box 1)
- Bofill, Riccardo (Box 1)
- Botta, Mario (Box 2)
- Breuer, Marcel (Box 2)
- Burlington [Richard Boyle, 3d earl of, 1695-1753] (Box 2)
- Cady, Josiah Cleveland (Box 2)
- Candella, Felix (Box 2)
- Carriere and Hastings (Box 2)
- Clerisseau [Charles Louis, 1721-1820] (Box 2)
- Davis, Alexander Jackson (Box 2)
- Desgodets, Antoine (Box 2)
- Dow, Alden 1904-1953 (Box 2)
- Ferris, Hugh (Box 2)
- Fisker, Kay (Box 2)
- Fontana, Domenico (Box 2)
- Ford, George Burdett (Box 2)
- Fuller, Buckminster (Box 2)
- Furness, Frank (Box 3)
- Gaudi, Antonio (Box 3)
- Gehry, Frank (Box 3)
- Gibbs, James 1682-1754 (Box 3)
- Giedion, Sigfried (Box 3)
- Gilbert, Cass (Box 3)
- Goff, Bruce (Box 3)
- Giurgola, Romaldo (Box 3)
- Goldberg, Bertrand (Box 3)
- Goodhue, Bertram (Box 3)
- Granger, Alfred Hoyt 1867-1934? (Box 3)
- Graves, Michael (Box 3)
- Greenberg, Allan (Box 3)
- Greene and Greene (Box 3)
- Gropius, Walter (Box 3)
- Gwathmey, Charles (Box 3)
- Haering, Hugo (Box 3)
- Hammond, Beeby [Thomas], & B (Box 3)
- Hawksmoor, Nicholas 1661-1736 (Box 3)
- Harrison, Walter (Box 3)
- Hertzberger, Herman (Box 3)
- Hertzog and de Meuron (Box 3)
- Halabird and Root (Box 3)
- Hood, Raymond (Box 3)
- Howe, George (Box 3)
- Jefferson, Thomas (Box 4)
- Jones, Inigo (Box 4)
- Johansen, John M. (Box 4)
- Johnson, Philip (Box 4)
- Kahn, Louis I. (Box 4)
- Koch, Karl (Box 4)
- Kohn Pederson and Fox (Box 4)
- Latrobe, Benjamin Henry 1764-1824 (Box 4)
- Laurano, Luciano [1420-1479] (Box 4)
- Le Corbusier (Box 4)
- Ledoux, Claude-Nicolas 1736-1806 (Box 4)
- Leonardo da Vinci (Box 4)
- Lescaze, William (Box 4)
- Levi, Rino 1901-1968 (Box 4)
- Lin, Maya (Box 4)
- L'Orme, Philibert de (Box 4)
- Lundy, Victor (Box 4)
- Lutyens, Edwin 1869-1904 (Box 5)
- Maher, George (Box 5)
- McKim Mead and White (Box 5)
- Mackintosh, Charles Rennie (Box 5)
- Maybeck, Bernard (Box 5)
- Meier, Richard (Box 5)
- Mendelson, Eric (Box 5)
- Mies van der Rohe (Box 5)
- Moore, Charles (Box 5)
- Nervi, Pier Luigi (Box 5)
- Neumann, Balthasar 1687-1753 (Box 5)
- Neutra, Richard (Box 5)
- Niemeyer, Oscar (Box 5)
- Nowicki, Matthew (Box 5)
- Okie, Richardson Brognard 1878-1945 (Box 5)
- Outram, John (Box 5)
- Palladio, Andrea (2 folders) (Box 6)
- Pei, I.M. (Box 6)
- Perret, Auguste 1874-1954 (Box 6)
- Post, George Brown (Box 6)
- Pugin, Augustus Welby Northmore (Box 6)
- Rainaldi, Carlo 1611-1691 (Box 6)
- Ramee, Joseph Jacques (Box 6)
- Raymond, Antonin (Box 6)
- Richardson, Henry Hobson (Box 6)
- Rogers, Richard (Box 6)
- Rossiter, Ehrick K. (Box 6)
- Rudolph, Paul (Box 6)
- Saarinen, Eero (Box 6)
- Saarinen, Eliel (Box 6)
- Scharoun, Hans (Box 7)
- Schindler, Rudolf M. (Box 7)
- Schinkel, Karl Friedrich (Box 7)
- Schweiker, Paul (Box 7)
- Sert, Jose Luis (Box 7)
- Shepley Bulfinch Richardson and Abbott (Box 7)
- Skidmore Owings and Merrill (Box 7)
- Smithson, Alison and Peter (Box 7)
- Soleri, Paolo (Box 7)
- Stirling, James (Box 7)
- Stone, Edward Durrell (Box 7)
- Stone, Sidney Mason 1803-1882 (Box 7)
- Stubbins, Hugh Jr. (Box 7)
- Taft Architects (Box 7)
- Tange, Kenzo (Box 7)
- Tefft, T. A. (Box 7)
- Tigerman, Stanley (Box 7)
- Town, Ithiel (Box 7)
- Trumbull, John (Box 8)
- Ungers, Simon and Laszlo Kiss (Box 8)
- Valk, Lawrence B (Box 8)
- Vanbrugh, John 1664-1726 (Box 8)
- Venturi, Robert (Box 8)
- Verhovskoy, Roman (Box 8)
- Vignola, G. B. 1507-1573 (Box 8)
- Viollet-le-Duc (2 folders) (Box 8)
- Voysey, C.F.A. (Box 8)
- Warnecke, John Carl (Box 8)
- Wood, William Halsey (Box 8)
- Wren, Christopher (Box 8)
- Wright, Frank Lloyd (Box 9)
- Wurster, William Wilson (Box 9)
- Yamasaki, Minoru (Box 9)
- Zambonini, Giuseppe (Box 9)